[Forging Justice]
[Episode 3]
Later,
ask Zheng to take you guys
to look around the street market
and to conduct an investigation.
Liu Erlin said
he mistook the person for someone else.
Then he and his defense lawyer
should figure out a way
to prove it.
Why should we
help him prove it?
That's not under the jurisdiction
of our court, is it?
Investigating evidence and finding clues
are the jobs
of the police and the procuratorate.
As long as we discover that
there's insufficient evidence
with unclear facts,
we should either send it back
for supplementary investigation
or just
acquit the suspect.
Why should we investigate it?
Alright.
Whether you go or not
is up to you.
[Nanyu County People's Court,
People's Procuratorate]
Chen Yizhong!
What does he mean?
Let's go.
Where are we going?
-Let's go.
-I don't know.
Um...
Where are we going?
[Nanyu County Legal Advisory Office]
Comrade, here's a letter for you.
Hello.
Who are you looking for?
We're students from the University
of Political Science and Law.
We're having an internship
in Nanyu County Court.
I remember you guys now.
I saw you all in court yesterday.
Come on. Have a seat.
Since you're court interns,
what are you
doing here?
We sat in on the trial
of Liu Erlin's case yesterday.
There are some questions
we'd like to ask you.
We can't talk to you about this case.
We're still busy.
It's fine.
As long as it's not against the rules,
we can talk about it.
Come on.
Have a seat.
No need. Don't bother.
Let me get you some water.
Actually, we have just one question.
Do you think Liu Erlin
was committing armed robbery,
or as he said in his defense,
he was just joking?
We think?
Does it matter what we think?
Of course it matters.
You are his defense lawyers.
Of course.
Liu Erlin's statement
might also be true.
Then why didn't you launch
a factual defense,
and why did you just say
he was a first-time
and casual offender?
In this way, weren't you admitting
that he committed armed robbery?
Li Xiang.
Thank you.
They have doubts.
Help them clear up the doubts.
Here's the thing.
Mr. Wang here
did that out of a desire to protect
the defendant.
If we plead not guilty,
and the court rejects it,
they might even say
the defendant has a bad attitude
towards admitting his crime,
which would be even worse
for the defendant instead.
Do you guys think
the question you asked
is particularly sharp?
Mr. Wang, we are students.
We just want to discuss...
So what if you're students?
Does that mean you can talk big
without substance?
Alright.
We're going to have a meeting.
We won't keep you any longer.
We won't disturb you anymore.
Thank you.
It's alright.
We are indeed busy.
Are you from the People's University
of Political Science and Law?
Yes.
How was it? Did you get anything?
Such institutions
are like deaf men's ears.
But at least deaf men's ears
have aesthetic effects.
It's not easy for them, either.
They are caught between the procuratorate
and the court.
According to what they said,
if you defend the case,
the sentencing will be enhanced instead.
Isn't that an exaggeration?
You'd better leave now.
Going to college
has made them all fools.
Actually, the question they asked
is what I've been thinking about, too.
Li Xiang.
What kind of situation is this now?
They don't punish
the hardworking or the lazy ones.
They only punish the blind ones.
I'm warning you.
Regarding the rape case
you're handling,
you must defend the case according to
the basic approach we've set.
Don't stick your neck out.
Well...
Isn't this more obvious?
It's adultery, not rape.
If you say so,
you can defend it yourself.
You don't know what's good for you.
That's perfect.
If you don't want to defend the case,
I can collaborate with Li Xiang.
You're intervening in everything,
aren't you?
I'll go get some hot water.
Wang.
Do you think this is okay?
I'll go ask Director Hong again.
Suit yourself.
Exactly.
I had thought that after being assigned
to the Justice Bureau,
I would at least get to
manage a few people.
I didn't expect
to be assigned to
such a crappy place.
Come...
Come in.
That's all for now.
I'll call you back later. Someone's here.
Have a seat.
My dear comrade-in-arms.
Director.
I have a case
that I'd like to consult you about.
What case is it? Tell me.
It's the case about a teacher
named Qiao Zhiliang
from the County No. 1 High School.
Oh, it's that case.
He's a beast.
He even laid his hands on
his own niece.
Didn't that girl
commit suicide later?
He should be executed.
He surely should be executed.
Well,
Director,
I've repeatedly reviewed
his case files,
and no matter how I've analyzed the case,
it just doesn't look like rape.
What are your reasons?
These two people
maintained a relationship
for at least over a year.
What's more,
the teachers and colleagues at the school
found out about it quite a long time ago.
Moreover, every time
he went to the victim's place,
he would stay there for several hours.
Sometimes,
he would even stay there overnight.
Just think about it.
How could there be such a rape?
The last time they did it,
his wife discovered them.
The girl felt ashamed.
Stuck in a negative mindset,
she committed suicide by drinking poison.
But this kind of thing isn't rare, either.
Li Xiang, what do you mean?
T-That girl
deserved it?
No, no, no.
I absolutely don't mean that.
Qiao Zhiliang
is absolutely a scumbag.
But the law is the law.
Try to put it simply.
I don't quite understand it.
The procuratorate
initiated a public prosecution
for rape resulting in death.
Rape
or adultery.
That's just one word's difference,
but it concerns a man's life and death.
So,
he doesn't deserve to die?
In the court of morality,
he deserves to die.
But in a real court,
I think we...
Alright, alright.
You don't need to explain it anymore.
You're saying that
even if he's a scumbag,
he still has the right to defend himself.
If he wants to defend himself,
we have to help him.
Is that what you mean?
Yes.
His family is from the city, right?
So you've sensed it?
He's from a family of lawyers.
What does that mean?
It's a family legacy.
Since childhood, he has known that
he wants to be a presiding judge.
You're back.
Did you get anything?
After working for a whole day,
we got nothing.
Mentor.
I think the criminal elements
of this case are basically complete.
If you still think that
the main facts are unclear,
we can return it to the procuratorate
for supplementary investigation
and to gather more evidence.
What are criminal elements?
You've never studied law before.
I can't explain it to you clearly
with a few words.
Mentor.
With the evidence we currently have,
we can actually acquit him
due to insufficient evidence.
I'm going home now.
What was he
laughing at just now?
He was laughing at our naivety.
What else could it be?
Are we still going tomorrow?
I'm not going tomorrow.
I need to make a long-distance call home.
There's something urgent.
I also have something to do tomorrow.
There's a task from Court Pres. Ding.
Let's leave it at that for now.
I've noticed that you seem a bit hostile
to Zheng Jianmin.
Did he offend you?
Today, he told me
he wanted to be a judge.
If it consists of all these people
who switch professions halfway
and make efforts at the last minute,
when will China's legal system
get on the right track?
I don't have the guts to criticize him.
You think you don't have the guts
to criticize him?
You almost accused him
of being ignorant of the law.
Where's Chen Yizhong?
Mentor!
Mentor! Mentor! Mentor!
Lu.
No, Yu.
Chen.
Chen, Chen.
Chen Yizhong.
Yes.
Several interns joined us all at once.
I can't tell you guys apart for a moment.
What's the matter?
Mentor.
I'd like to ask
whether you don't think
Liu Erlin's case was robbery at all.
Are you saying
I'm intentionally covering for him?
Of course not.
I know.
You guys watched the trial
and think us people
in the grassroots court
don't know the law
and are unprofessional with no principles,
merely messing around.
No, that's not what I mean.
Liu Erlin is indeed a loafer.
But to say he had the guts
to rob others...
If you say I'm prejudiced
by first impressions,
maybe a little.
But to say I'm covering for him,
I wouldn't dare.
It's a critical period now.
We're cracking down hard
on criminal offenses.
If I'm too lenient or too strict,
it might affect
a person's whole life.
Then what if...
What if we can't
find new witnesses later?
Then just let him imprisoned
for the rest of his life.
Let him rot in jail.
Aren't you contradicting yourself?
Mentor.
I think it's precisely because
of this period
that we should make more efforts
to prove Liu Erlin's innocence.
How do you know
he's innocent?
Just because of a few words I said to you?
No.
Before the court finds him guilty,
I presume every defendant
is innocent.
Presume?
Right.
If this presumption of yours
is stated in court,
at this current period,
it's not much louder than a fart.
If you think it's troublesome,
you don't have to go look for it.
He's just unlucky.
[Nanyu County Detention Center]
Why do you have to
defend him?
Hey, wait a minute!
What is this?
It's just a recorder.
Are you from the TV station
or the Legal Advisory Office?
I'm a lawyer.
This equipment
can't be used in our place.
Comrade.
I'm coming here alone to see my client.
I'll just record the process.
If something happens later,
this can also protect us.
Then I have to ask my supervisor.
Then go ask him.
Hello, Qiao Zhiliang.
My name is Li Xiang.
The Legal Advisory Office sent me here
to be your lawyer.
Do you agree
to entrust me to defend you?
Quit defending me.
Qiao Zhiliang.
Here's the thing.
The law stipulates that
cases with a potential death penalty
must have a defender.
Here is the Defense Authorization Letter.
If you agree,
just sign it.
The indictment
accuses you
of raping your wife's niece,
Wei Sanmei.
Regarding this,
do you have anything to say?
No.
So you
admit that you raped her?
Was it rape
or adultery?
Five kids?
That judge
brought five kids to work.
If the litigants had seen that,
how much would the judge's authority
be affected?
I even helped change a diaper.
I was clumsy
and got the baby's poop all over my hand.
Oh, right.
It was this hand.
Smell it. Does it stink?
Come on.
I don't have the habit
of having congee at night.
What's more, she even
graduated from Xihua University
of Political Science and Law.
That's what makes it such a pity.
As a graduate of Xihua University
of Political Science and Law,
she came back here to have five kids.
Her college education was a waste.
But her professional skills
are very strong.
There are no cases for her to try today.
But she brought the kids
and read case files all day.
She even met with two litigants.
Right?
She's quite good at reading case files.
By reading through a file just once,
she can summarize all the key points
in the file clearly.
In the same time,
she can also identify
all the problems in the file clearly.
It's very incredible.
Let's observe her for now.
If it's really not okay,
I'll tell Court Pres. Ding
about this
to change your mentor.
We're here to be interns,
not to change diapers.
I don't want that.
We just like changing diapers.
I shouldn't have suggested it.
They just want to change diapers.
[Nanyu County People's Court,
People's Procuratorate]
Today,
we are looking at a murder case.
The defendant, Qiu Agui,
was not even 17
when her parents
made her engaged to someone.
Their purpose was to trade their daughter
for a bride price
so that her younger brother
could use it to get married.
At that time, her brother
wasn't even 14.
In rural Nanyu,
husbands beating their wives
is quite common.
After Qiu Agui got married,
she was beaten on the second day.
She was beaten continuously
until she became a mother
of three children.
Believe it or not, I'll beat you to death!
As for when exactly
Qiu Agui got
this idea,
she probably
couldn't even explain it well herself.
But with even just a little hope,
a person
wouldn't take this desperate path.
Mom, I'm scared!
Don't be scared.
Your dad
won't beat us anymore.
I killed my husband.
The procuratorate
suggested the death penalty.
It's been pending for my decision
for two months.
Mentor,
this is a county-level court.
Can we also try death penalty cases?
We couldn't do that before.
But aren't we
in the Strike-Hard Campaign now?
So county-level courts
can also try death penalty cases.
The power of death penalty review
used to be owned by the Supreme Court.
Now it's been delegated
to the province-level courts.
It's been so many years
since the founding of New China.
How can people
still trade their own daughters
for bride prices?
Because they are poor.
Yes.
The most tragic victims
of poverty and wars are usually
women and children.
To improve women's fate,
we need to start with improving
economy and education.
Our mentor graduated from Xihua University
of Political Science and Law.
Isn't she back...
Well, what did Zhang mean?
He didn't elaborate on the details,
just waiting for us to run our legs off.
Actually, what he said was very simple.
Just one word—
evidence.
We've been overlooking
one thing all along.
Liu Erlin said
he mistook the person for someone else.
But as for who he mistook that person for,
we don't know about it.
Right?
If we can find this person,
it might be a breakthrough.
Will the court accept it?
There are still two words—
inner conviction.
If we find this person
and compare the two people,
confirming that their backs
really look alike,
then Liu Erlin was probably
just joking, right?
And then with the other factors
in this case,
we can basically confirm
that Liu Erlin was just joking,
so he can't be sentenced for robbery.
Alright.
Stop playing
word games with me.
Just tell me
what Zhang meant.
He's just like an old fox.
And what about Yu Gaoyuan?
Why isn't he here?
Does he think this case is too small
and too troublesome?
He's so sly.
Something came up at his home, didn't it?
He couldn't come even if he wanted to.
Let's go.
Even if you can't save Du Xiaohui,
at least you can save yourself.
This incident will haunt you
for the rest of your life.
Come on.
Let's go back.
Which place are we going back to?
Let's go back and keep asking.
Even if it might take a year
to ask about it,
we still need to find the witness.
Let's go.
Well,
we've already asked up to 100 people.
During this one-year internship,
we have to look for witnesses
for half a year?
He was just joking with that person.
Liu Erlin's brain
doesn't work well.
It's like something is missing up there.
If you ask me,
it's good to put him in jail
and teach him a lesson there
for a couple of days.
Are you...
Are you a reporter?
No, I'm from the court.
Wasn't he just joking?
Is it so serious that he'll be sentenced?
It depends on how the case is classified.
If it's considered as robbery,
he'll be sentenced to 15 years.
If he was just joking,
he'll just be detained for 15 days.
Bro.
You just said Liu Erlin
might have mistaken the person
for someone else.
Who did he mistake him for?
I'm thinking
whether it was Laishun.
Laishun?
Liu Erlin always bullied him.
Where does this Laishun live?
He's dead.
A couple of days ago,
he was run over and killed by a big truck
that was transporting timber.
Who's dead?
You're all here.
Sit down.
-Court Pres. Ding.
I'm wondering
when Qiu Agui's case
will go to trial.
Can we
get a suspended death sentence for her?
Their father is already dead.
Let's leave a mother for the three kids.
Fang Shumei,
could you just see how the situation is?
Her husband's family
gathered dozens of people
to make trouble
at the county government every day.
Alright.
Look at this.
They've even sent us a letter
written in blood.
The county government
keeps calling us like crazy.
If we don't convict her soon,
there will be chaos.
This is intentional homicide.
But Court Pres. Ding,
I understand
she was afraid of being beaten to death.
She struck first
because she was so terrified.
Strictly speaking,
it could be considered
as justifiable defense.
It looks like I'm still
lacking in professional knowledge.
Alright, Young Comrade.
Come on.
Explain to me
what justifiable defense is.
Justifiable defense means...
When her husband was drunk,
she hacked him dozens of times,
chopping off half of his face,
which even made him unrecognizable.
So this is justifiable defense?
Is it, college student?
Court Pres. Ding.
Speak.
Considering that her husband
often beat her up,
can we give her a lighter punishment?
You've received so much education.
Have you ever taken a lesson like this?
That is, when the law
cannot be separated from
social reality,
what should we do?
The so-called social reality
you've mentioned
is that men
can beat their wives up as they please,
but once women resist,
they will be punished by law, right?
The social reality here in our place
is poverty
and underdevelopment.
Many men
would beat their wives.
You can't say that.
Stop, stop, stop.
I know what you're going to say.
Of course I know
this is a bad habit.
I have always believed
that men who beat their wives
are all scumbags,
and they should all be arrested.
I've said that, haven't I?
You've always said that.
But don't forget that
this concept and such behavior
cannot be changed by us
in a short term.
Isn't this also social reality?
Currently, the situation
is already like this.
Let me tell you all.
If we don't sentence her
to death in this case,
in the future,
there might be more and more incidents
of wives hacking their husbands.
This logic is twisted
so greatly.
Why don't you say Qiu Agui
made an example of him
so that those scumbags
would never
dare to beat their wives again?
Well, she...
Court Pres. Ding.
She doesn't mean you're twisted.
Isn't he twisted?
He's just twisted.
Um, does this mean...
Twisted.
I'm twisted, okay?
I... I can't outdebate you guys.
As for the current situation,
you all know about it.
Fang Shumei.
Handle it yourself.
Ms. Fang.
You're calling me Ms. Fang?
Is that strange?
You have the highest level of education
in our court.
Do you think
according to the new criminal law,
she deserves the death penalty?
Yes, she does.
Even if Laishun were still alive,
and even if he looked like the victim,
that's just an inference.
In court,
it can't be used as evidence.
Since it's something so basic,
don't you guys know that?
Zhang is just deliberately
giving us a hard time.
It can't be used as evidence indeed,
but it can affect
the fairness of the trial.
You're using such big words.
Hey, sir.
Stop pacing around.
In addition,
why are you making so many snide remarks?
What snide remarks did I make?
We almost ran our legs off.
But what did you do?
Were you staying indoors
and thinking about
where the Chinese legal system
should head?
Haven't I told you something urgent
has come up in my family latley?
So you're the only one with issues?
Why do you have so many issues?
The whole country
can't do without you, huh?
Zeming,
I've tolerated you for a long time.
Do you know that?
Have I asked you to tolerate me?
Just hit me!
Don't you guys think
you're are so childish?
Um...
Well, why is she angry?
Today, we studied
a husband-killing case with our mentor.
It must have affected her mood.
What husband-killing case?
Why?
Because of suffering and injustice.
When she was in desperation,
no one helped her.
When she resisted,
she was punished by the law.
It's alright. I'm used to it.
He always makes snide remarks.
I know you're in a very bad mood.
What happened?
Tell me about it.
It's just about the tricky issues
in the village.
You wouldn't be interested.
You're like this again.
Isn't there the household contract
responsibility system?
Our family got six mu of land.
Only two mu of it is good.
Now they want to exchange bad land
for the two mu of good land.
They say it's an exchange,
but they actually want to take it away.
How could this happen?
It sounds like a joke, right?
But it's a big deal in our village.
I called the brigade today,
saying that I wanted to talk to my dad.
They deliberately didn't let him
answer the phone.
I think you should go home.
What can I do if I go back?
Shall I fight with the village secretary?
No.
As long as you go back,
it'll be helpful to your family.
At least it'll be a comfort
to your parents.
Yu Gaoyuan.
I've sterilized it with hot water.
It's filled with cold boiled water.
You can drink it on the way.
Thank you.
Take the food, too.
They don't accept grain ration coupons
on the train.
Buying food is expensive.
When you go back home, do your best
to reason with that village secretary.
Though you have to reason with him,
don't be impulsive.
Don't worry.
Zhang Lihui!
Have a safe trip.
What's wrong?
Okay.
You haven't packed much stuff.
I can do it myself.
Thank you.
You were the one
who helped me make up my mind.
Let me do it.
Yu.
These are...
some national grain ration coupons.
Take them with you.
I'm leaving.
Why are you giving me so many of them?
What about you guys
if you give them to me?
Lu collected them.
He was too embarrassed to come himself,
so he asked me
to apologize to you for him.
Don't take it to heart.
I'm not as petty as he is.
Thanks for your help in the next few days.
Don't worry.
Be careful.
Do you need to pack all this stuff?
No need.
Liu Bingsheng
has been a juror here
for three years.
Just find him.
He's a man.
Not every man in Nanyu
would beat his wife.
At least I wouldn't.
Are you married?
No.
Don't worry.
Well, I mean, trust me.
Just find Liu as he's the right person.
Okay.
Thank you.
You're welcome. I'll get going then.
Bye.
This is yours.
Thanks, Gaoyuan.
Take it inside the house and eat it.
Your dad is a teacher,
but he can't even settle this small issue.
Why did he ask you
to come back?
Who asked Gaoyuan to come back?
I didn't.
Mom.
I came back voluntarily.
As for my dad's issue, we're in the right.
We have a land contract with the village
which will remain unchanged for 15 years.
Unless we're voluntary,
they're just coercing us.
The village secretary
knows he's in the wrong.
Otherwise,
he wouldn't have used that trick.
What trick?
On the surface,
the Tang family
is complaining about unfairness
and wants to swap land with us.
But secretly,
he's the one pulling the strings.
After swapping land with us,
the Tang family will then
transfer it to him.
Everyone knows what's going on,
but no one has the guts to point it out.
We can only swallow the bitter pill.
I'll go find the village secretary later.
You can't go.
Why can't I go?
I'm going to reason with him,
not to fight with him.
It's useless.
Why are you saying that it's useless?
It's already been swapped.
Gaoyuan! Gaoyuan!
Thirty-eight.
Gaoyuan is back.
Gaoyuan.
You're the first college student
in our village.
When you went to Beijing to study...
Let me tell you.
I even gave your dad
20 yuan to support you.
Is that so?
I'll go back and ask my dad.
If that's true,
we'll raise the money to return it to you.
How could you say that?
Come on! Have a seat!
Sit.
Sit down.
Have a seat.
I heard your family
was allocated several mu of land.
Four mu.
Later,
they insisted on swapping two mu
with the Tang family,
making it six mu in total.
Aren't you talking nonsense?
Two mu of our land was...
Alright.
Let's not talk about this today.
Okay?
What's your major in college?
Law.
I'm majoring in law...
at the University
of Political Science and Law.
After graduation,
I can be assigned to the court
or the procuratorate.
I've also thought about it.
If that's not okay,
I'll come back to the county or the town
and work in the judicial department.
Village Secretary,
please look after me then.
If you're assigned back here,
I won't agree.
You're so knowledgeable.
You finally got a chance to go to Beijing
and study at a university.
If you come back
to such a poor place,
wouldn't it be a waste
of your great talents?
In Beijing,
you can play a bigger role.
Whether I stay in Beijing or not
is my own business.
Today,
we're talking about land allocation.
Accountant Tang,
gather the two families tomorrow
and do as Gaoyuan says.
Mr. Tang's three sons won't agree.
They won't just
watch themselves suffer losses,
will they?
Losses are blessings.
Who doesn't suffer losses sometimes?
It's not about suffering losses or not.
It's about the stipulation
of the land policy.
Just listen to me.
Speaking of policies,
logically speaking,
your dad is a teacher,
so he shouldn't be allocated any land.
My dad doesn't have an official position.
He works at a private school.
So what if he works at a private school?
You can't have it all.
Your dad both receives salaries
from the government
and wants to gain an official position.
Now you're even asking for land.
Well,
you guys got all the good stuff.
As for our villagers,
I have to give them
an explanation.
You used to be a student cadre, too.
What's the most important thing
for a cadre?
It's to treat everyone
with absolute equality.
The most important thing for a cadre
is to be fair and impartial,
not to treat everyone
with absolute equality.
If you don't treat everyone
with absolute equality...
How could they be the same?
How are they different?
If you don't...
Indeed.
Village Secretary.
Gaoyuan didn't say
anything offensive, did he?
No, he didn't.
We were just talking about
your teaching qualification.
Aren't you going to swap the land?
Accountant,
help them swap the land tomorrow.
No need. It's really not necessary.
I beg you. No need.
Okay? Listen to me.
What?
Gaoyuan.
Calm down.
You can't go.
You can't go. Calm down.
-What?
-Calm down.
Chen Yizhong.
Hey,
are you addicted to this?
Are you going to
ask bluntly just like that?
What could you possibly find out?
If you don't ask,
won't it be harder for you to find out?
Exactly.
It won't hurt to ask.
Didn't you guys get the testimony
from Liu Erlin by asking?
How could that be the same?
Qiu Agui's case
is about killing her husband.
It's only been a few days,
and my legs have gotten thicker
from all this riding.
Besides,
why can't you two
ride your own bikes?
Why do you need others to give you a ride?
As a grown man,
you should contribute your strength.
Lihui!
Get on my bike!
I have something to tell you.
You're not as heavy as she is.
You...
-Get on the bike.
-Let's go.
Cushion your butt.
Let's go.
Let's go!
How about I ride for a while?
Hya!
What?
Go!
Hurry!
Get out!
Ma'am! Ma'am!
If you don't get out now,
I'll call for help!
Don't be angry, Ma'am.
My son died such a tragic death,
but you're
still speaking for the murderer.
Get out!
All of you, get out!
W-We're not speaking for anyone.
We want to know the truth.
Ma'am!
Ma'am! Ma'am!
Are you okay?
What is this and why is it so smelly?
Pig manure.
Just... Just stand there.
Don't move.
I'm dirty.
Don't come near me!
Like mother,
like son.
If you were her,
in terms of your personality,
you might have poured acid on us.
You have a good personality.
You're tough.
I don't think it's useful to ask her.
Why?
In the countryside,
blood ties are more important
than anything else.
If you don't believe me, go ask them.
Alright. I'll go ask them.
You... Stop.
It's not clean yet.
Lower your head.
Just take a break.
The smell on you
will scare them all away.
Let me do it.
Ma'am!
Hello, we...
We... We are not bad people.
Here you are. Wipe your hair.
Wipe your hair.
Hello, we are from the county court.
We want to learn about
the situation of Huang Liancang's family.
Alright.
I think the people in this village
are hopeless.
To them,
Qiu Agui is an outsider.
Outsider?
Well...
Didn't they all marry into this village
from other places?
That's different.
Well, what Lihui means is...
what Qiu Agui did this time
wasn't just murder.
This time, she hurt
the entire village's pride and feelings.
Her husband beating her
was their own family business.
Now that she has killed him
just for beating her,
how can other families
enforce their family rules in the future?
Right?
Being tied down here,
they can't bear it or escape.
Then they often go to extremes
or even commit suicide.
Previously, I heard
the sociology department say that
the suicide rate among rural women
was alarmingly high.
The figures would shock you.
So we came here in vain?
I refuse to accept it!
Will it help if you refuse to accept it?
Even if you find something out,
would they
provide their testimonies for you?
How would they continue to
stay in this village after that?
So we're just going to watch her
get sentenced to death
and do nothing, huh?
Let me say something you won't like.
We're running around here
like headless chickens,
and that's more about
satisfying ourselves.
Why do you have to be so mean?
How am I satisfying myself?
A helpless sense of justice.
I'm talking about not just you
but also myself.
I'm not like Yu Gaoyuan,
who always excludes himself
before criticizing others.
I'm better at self-criticism.
When you're talking, your mouth...
You're really annoying.
Let me tell you. You're always like that.
Y-You can give her a ride.
Take care of her.
I have to get this straight with you.
How am I satisfying myself?
I'm not...
Slow down!
What should we do now?
Comrades.
If we miss this chance,
there won't be another one.
Comrades.
A-Are you from the court?
Yes.
We are all from the county court.
My name is Xia Yingjie.
Are you also from this village?
Sort of.
But not exactly.
Qiu Agui and I are from the same village.
We married into this one together.
Just like her,
I get beaten by my husband every day.
My husband's name is Feng Dazhi.